interhome.com 2018-12-27

# Privacy policy | Interhome

**Data Privacy Policy**  
In the following we provide information about the collection of personal data when using our website. Personal data is all data that can be personally attributed to you, for example name, address, email addresses. 

 **Contents**

1\. Identity of the data controller  
2\. Information on the collection of personal data when you visit our website  
3\. Use of cookies   
4\. Types of cookies  
5\. How can cookies be prevented?  
6\. Information about the collection of personal data when contacting us by email or via the contact form   
7\. Information about the collection of personal data when making a booking through our website   
8\. Newsletter   
9\. Newsletter tracking   
10\. Use of Google Analytics   
11\. Use of Facebook Plugin   
12.Use of Google Maps   
13\. Use of Google Tag Manager   
14\. Google Adwords   
15\. Use of Facebook Custom Audiences   
16\. DoubleClick by Google  
17. Iridion optimization Suite  
18\. Send recommendations to friends or receive recommendations   
19\. Disclosure of your personal data to other recipients   
20\. Your rights as the affected person (data subject)

 **1\. Identity of the data controller**  
Data controller pursuant to Art. 4(7) of the EU General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) is 

Interhome AG   
Sägereistrasse 27  
CH 8152 Glattbrugg   
Phone: +41 43 810 91 91  
Fax: +41 43 810 91 90  
Email: info@interhome.ch   
Data Protection Coordinator for Interhome AG  
Andreas Benz  
DSB@interhome.com or DPO@interhome.com  
Representative pursuant to Art. 27 GDPR  
Attorney Prof. Clemens Pustejovsky  
DSB@interchalet.com or DPO@interchalet.com  
Wallstr. 6, D-79098 Freiburg, Phone: 076172168680

 **2\. Information on the collection of personal data when you visit our website**  
If you only use our website for informational purposes without providing us with any other infor-mation, we only collect the personal data that your browser transmits to our server. If you wish to view our website, we collect data that is technically necessary for us to display our website to you and to guarantee stability and security (legal basis is Art. 6(1)(1)(f) GDPR). This data includes:

  * IP address of the accessing computer
  * date and time of access
  * URL of the accessed page
  * status message about whether the access was successful
  * quantity of data transferred
  * the referrer URL from which the user came to the accessed page
  * HTTP user agent (device, operating system, browser) 

**3\. Use of cookies**  
When you use our website, cookies are also stored on your computer, i.e. small text files which are stored on your hard disk and assigned to the browser you use, and through which certain information is sent to us as cookies. We use cookies to make our website more user-friendly and effective (the legal basis for this is Art. 6(1)(f) GDPR).

 **4\. Types of cookies**  
On our website we use transient cookies, such as session cookies, which store a session ID. With this, different requests of your browser can be assigned to the common session so that your com-puter can be recognized when you visit our website again. Session cookies and transient cookies are deleted when you close your browser or log out.   
We also use persistent cookies for the "Wish List" function on our website so that the contents of your Wish List are not lost and you can view your selected holiday objects again at a later date. After 28 days, these cookies are automatically deleted from your hard drive. Regardless of this, you can delete the cookies in the security settings of your browser at any time.

 **5\. How can cookies be prevented?  **  
It is possible for you to prevent the acceptance of third party cookies or all cookies, for example, by making the appropriate settings in your browser. However, this may mean that you may not be able to use all the functions of our website.

 **6\. Information about the collection of personal data when contacting us by email or via the contact form**  
If you contact us by email or via the contact form on our website, the data provided by you (email address, or, if applicable, your first and last name, your telephone number or other data) provided by you will be processed by us to answer your questions (the legal basis for this is Art. 6(1)(1)(b) GDPR or Art. 6(1)(1)(f) GDPR). We delete the data arising in connection with the establishment of contact after the storage is no longer necessary, or we limit the processing, if legal storage obligations exist.

 **7\. Information about the collection of personal data when making a booking through our website**  
(1) If you wish to book a holiday home or apartment through our website, you must provide the fol-lowing information: Your name, your address, your email address, your telephone number. The provi-sion of further information is voluntary. Pursuant to Art. 6(1)(b) GDPR, the processing of your data is necessary for the fulfilment of a contract with us or for the implementation of pre-contractual measures, as we cannot conclude the contract or carry out pre-contractual measures without these.   
(2) Due to commercial and tax regulations, we are obliged to store your address, payment, and order data for a period of ten years. However, we limit the processing after two years, i.e. your data will only be used to comply with legal storage obligations.  
(3) The connection is encrypted using TLS technology to prevent unauthorized access to your per-sonal data. 

 **8\. Newsletter**  
(1) We may also process the data you provide when concluding a contract in order to inform you about other interesting products in our portfolio or to send you emails containing technical infor-mation. Of course, you can object to the processing of your personal data for the purposes of advertising and data analysis at any time. You can notify us about your objection to advertising using the following contact information: Interhome AG, Sägereistrasse 27, CH 8152 Glattbrugg, Phone: +49 2421 12 20, Fax: +49 2421 12 22 99, Email: info@interhome.de  
(2) On our website we offer you the opportunity to register for our newsletter. We use the data provid-ed in this context to inform you about other interesting products / services from our offer (the legal basis for this is then Art. 6(1)(1)(a) GDPR).   
If we process your data on the basis of your consent, you can revoke this consent at any time. The revocation does not affect the legality of the processing carried out on the basis of the consent be-fore the revocation. If you wish to revoke your consent, please use the following contact information: Interhome AG, Sägereistrasse 27, CH 8152 Glattbrugg, Phone: +49 2421 12 20, Fax: +49 2421 12 22 99, Email: [info@interhome.de](mailto:info@interhome.de)

 **9\. Newsletter tracking**  
When sending newsletters, we use so-called web beacons or tracking pixels. A web beacon or track-ing pixel is a single-pixel image file embedded in the newsletter and displayed to you from a remote server when you open the newsletter. We use these to evaluate your user behaviour (the legal basis for this is Art. 6(1)(1)(a) GDPR). To this end, the data mentioned in the "Information about the collec-tion of personal data when visiting our website" section and the following information are linked to your email address and an individual ID: (i) confirmation that the email has been opened; (ii) timestamp; (iii) links that have been clicked; (iv) content that has been viewed. This data is used to create a user profile and to better tailor the newsletter to your interests. This helps us to better under-stand the extent to which our offers are of interest to you. We record when you read our newsletter and which links you click on. This data is also linked to your activities on our website.   
The information collected in this way is stored by us as long as you have subscribed to the newslet-ter. As soon as you log out, the data is stored statistically and anonymously.You have the possibility to object to this tracking at any time. You can inform us about your ob-jection using the following contact data: Interhome AG, Sägereistrasse 27, CH 8152 Glatt-brugg, Phone: +49 2421 12 20,  
Fax: +49 2421 12 22 99, Email: [info@interhome.de](mailto:info@interhome.de)

 **10\. Use of Google Analytics**  
(1) On our website, we use the web analytics service Google Analytics of Google Inc. ("Google"). Google Analytics uses cookies, which enables an analysis of your use of the website. We are inter-ested in analysing our website, improving it regularly, and making it more interesting for you (the legal basis for this is Art. 6(1)(1)(f) GDPR).  
(2) The information generated in this way is regularly transmitted to a Google server in the USA and stored there. Google is compliant with the EU-US Privacy Shield, https://www.privacyshield.gov/EU-US-Framework.  
(3) We have commissioned Google to evaluate the information thus obtained about your use of our website in order to compile reports about website activities and to provide us with further services connected with the use of the website and the internet. However, the IP address transmitted by your browser is not merged with other Google data.  
(4) If you wish to prevent cookies from being stored, you can do so by making the appropriate set-tings in your browser. However, this can result in not all functions of our website being fully usable. In addition, you can prevent Google from collecting and processing data relating to your use of the website (including your IP address) by downloading and installing the browser plugin available at the following link: http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=de.  
(5) This website uses Google Analytics with the extension "_anonymizeIp()", which shortens the pro-cessing of IP addresses. In this way a personal relationship can be excluded. As far as the data col-lected about you is personal, it will be excluded immediately and the personal data will be deleted immediately.  
(6) Information about Google can be found at: Google Dublin, Google Ireland Ltd., Gordon House, Barrow Street, Dublin 4, Ireland, Fax: +353 (1) 436 1001.   
User conditions: http://www.google.com/analytics/terms/de.html,   
Overview of data protection: http://www.google.com/intl/de/analytics/learn/privacy.html  
Privacy Policy: [http://www.google.de/intl/de/policies/privacy](https://www.google.de/intl/de/policies/privacy).

 **11\. Use of Facebook Plugin**  
(1) We use social media plugins from Facebook Inc, 1601 S California Ave, Palo Alto, California 94304, USA, on our website, giving you the opportunity to interact with Facebook and other users. This helps us to improve our offer and to make it more interesting for you as a user (the legal basis for this is Art. 6(1)(1)(f) GDPR).  
(2) When using the plugin, we use the so-called two-click solution, so that in principle no personal data is initially passed on to Facebook. If you click the respective Facebook button (see Facebook logo) on our website and thereby activate it, you have the possibility to communicate directly with Facebook. In this case, Facebook will receive information regarding which (sub)page of our website you have accessed and, if applicable, shared or liked. Additionally, the data specified in Information about the collection of personal data when visiting our website is transmitted and stored in the USA; by activating the plugin, your personal data is forwarded to Facebook. According to Facebook, how-ever, the IP address is made anonymous immediately after it is collected.   
(3) The data collected about you will be stored by Facebook as user profiles and used for purposes of advertising, market research, and/or demand-oriented design of the Facebook website. The evalua-tion takes place in particular (also for users who are not logged in) for the purpose of displaying de-mand-oriented advertising and to inform other Facebook users about your activities on our website.   
(4) You have the right to object to the creation of these user profiles, and you must contact Face-book to exercise this right.   
(5) The data will also be passed on if you do not have a Facebook account or are not logged in there. However, if you are logged in, the information we collect will be directly associated with your Face-book account. For example, if you activate the button, then click and link to our website, Facebook stores this information about you in your user account and shares it publicly with your contacts. To avoid this attribution, we recommend that you log out of your Facebook account before activating the button.   
(6) If you live outside the United States or Canada, the responsible party for personal data (data con-troller) is Facebook Ireland Ltd, 4 Grand Canal Square, Grand Canal Harbour, Dublin 2, Ireland.  
Further information on the processing of your data, the purpose and scope of data collection by Fa-cebook, and your rights, as well as settings options for protecting your privacy, are available using the links provided below:  
Facebook Inc., 1601 S California Ave, Palo Alto, California 94304, USA http://www.facebook.com/policy.php;   
Further information on data collection: http://www.facebook.com/help/186325668085084, http://www.facebook.com/about/privacy/your-info-on-other#applications   
as well as http://www.facebook.com/about/privacy/your-info#everyoneinfo.   
Facebook is compliant with the EU-US-Privacy-Shield, <https://www.privacyshield.gov/EU-US-Framework>.

 **12\. Use of Google Maps**  
(1) We use Google Maps on our website to display interactive maps on our website. In addition, we can enable you to use the map function (the legal basis for this is Art. 6(1)(1)(f) GDPR).  
(2) When you visit our website, Google obtains information regarding which (sub)page of our website you have accessed. When this happens, the data mentioned in Information about the collection of personal data when visiting our website is also transmitted, regardless of whether you have a Google account and are logged in or not, or if no user account exists. However, if you are logged in, your information will be directly associated with your Google Account. To avoid this assignment, we rec-ommend that you log out of your Google Account before activating the button.  
(3) The data collected about you will be stored by Google as user profiles and used for purposes of advertising, market research and/or demand-oriented design of Google websites. The evaluation takes place in particular (also for users who are not logged) for the representation of demand-oriented advertisement and for the purpose of informing other users of Google about your activities on our website.   
(4) You have the right to object to the creation of these user profiles, and you must contact Google to exercise this right.   
(5) Further information on the processing of your data as well as on the purpose and scope of data collection by Google, and on your rights and settings options for the protection of your privacy, is available using the links provided below:  
Google LLC., 1600 Amphitheater Parkway, Mountain View, California 94043, USA; https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/partners/?hl=de.   
https://policies.google.com/privacy?hl=de  
Google is compliant with the EU-US Privacy Shield, <https://www.privacyshield.gov/EU-US-Framework>

 **13\. Use of Google Tag Manager**  
We use the Google Tag Manager. This is a solution that allows us to manage website tags from a single interface. The Tag Manager itself (which implements the tags) is a cookieless domain and does not process any personal data of users. The tool triggers other tags, which in turn may collect data. According to Google, Google Tag Manager does not access this data. For more information, see the Google Tag Manager usage guidelines at https://www.google.com/intl/de/tagmanager/use-policy.html.  
14\. Google Adwords  
(1) We use Google Adwords to draw attention to our offers on external websites and can thus deter-mine how successful our individual advertising measures are. Our legitimate interest in this is to make our website more interesting for you and to show you interesting advertising. Furthermore, we would like to calculate our advertising costs (the legal basis for the processing of your data is Art. 6(1)(f) GDPR).  
(2) Google Adwords are delivered via ad servers. Here, ad server cookies are used to measure cer-tain parameters for measuring success, such as the insertion of ads or clicks by users. If you access our website via a Google ad, Google Adwords stores a conversion cookie with limited validity (30 days) on your PC, which is not used to identify you personally. The following analysis values are usu-ally stored with this cookie: Unique cookie ID, number of ad impressions per placement (frequency), last impression (relevant for post view conversions), and opt-out information (flag that the user no longer wishes to be addressed).  
(3) Google can recognize your browser with the help of the cookie. So if the cookie hasn't expired, Google and we can recognize that you clicked an ad and were directed to our site and whether you generated any revenue. However, it is not possible for us to identify you as a user. We only receive a statistical evaluation from Google to check the effectiveness of the advertising measures used.   
(4) Due to the marketing tool used, personal data is transferred to Google in the United States of America and stored there each time you visit our website. These include, for example, the websites you visit and your IP address. Google may share this personal information with third parties. Adddi-tionally, if you are registered with a Google service, Google can attribute your visit to your account.   
(5) If you want to prevent this, you can do so in various ways:   
a) Suppression of third party cookies via a setting in your browser  
b) Blocking cookies from the domains www.googleadservices.com and https://www.google.de/settings/ads, whereby this setting will be deleted if you delete your cookies;   
c) by deactivating the interest-based ads of the providers that are part of the "About Ads" self-regulation campaign via the link http://www.aboutads.info/choices, this setting being deleted if you delete your cookies;   
d) by permanent deactivation in your browsers: http://www.google.com/settings/ads/plugin.   
(6) Further information on data protection at Google can be found here: http://www.google.com/intl/de/policies/privacy and https://services.google.com/sitestats/de.html. Google is compliant with the EU-US Privacy Shield, <https://www.privacyshield.gov/EU-US-Framework>.

 **15\. Use of Facebook Custom Audiences**  
Our website uses "Custom Audiences", a remarketing function of Facebook Inc. ("Facebook"). This function allows you, as a user of our website, to see interest-based ads ("Facebook ads") when you visit the social network Facebook or other websites that also use the process. Our interest in this is to display interesting advertising for you and to make our website more interesting for you (the legal basis for processing your data is Art. 6(1)(f) GDPR).  
By using this function, your browser automatically establishes a direct connection to the Facebook server. The extent to which the data collected in this way is actually collected and used is beyond our exact knowledge and influence. However, we are aware that Facebook will always receive the infor-mation that you have visited the corresponding page on our website, or that you have clicked on an ad from us. If you are registered with Facebook, Facebook can associate your visit with your ac-count. Even if you do not have an account on Facebook or are logged out, Facebook may still know and store your IP address and other identifying information.You can disable the feature "Facebook Custom Audiences". Logged in users can deactivate it here: https://www.facebook.com/settings/?tab=ads#_  
For more information about Facebook and Facebook's data processing, please visit <https://www.facebook.com/about/privacy>

 **16\. DoubleClick by Google**  
(1) This website uses the online marketing tool DoubleClick by Google. DoubleClick uses cookies to serve ads relevant to users, improve campaign performance reports, or prevent a user from seeing the same ads more than once. Google uses a cookie ID to track which ads are displayed in which browser and to prevent them from being displayed more than once. In addition, DoubleClick may use cookie IDs to collect conversions related to ad requests. This is the case, for example, when a user sees a DoubleClick ad and later visits the advertiser's website with the same browser and buys some-thing there. According to Google, DoubleClick cookies do not contain any personal information.  
(2) Due to the marketing tools used, your browser automatically establishes a direct connection with the Google server. We have no influence on the extent and further use of the data collected by Google through the use of this tool and therefore provide you with this information according to the extent of our knowledge: By integrating DoubleClick, Google receives information that you have ac-cessed the corresponding part of our website or clicked on an ad from us. If you are registered with a Google service, Google may associate your visit with your account. Even if you are not registered with Google or have not logged in, it is possible that the provider may obtain and store your IP ad-dress.  
(3) You can prevent participation in this tracking procedure in various ways: a) by setting your browser software accordingly, in particular by suppressing third-party cookies, you will not receive any ads from third-party providers; b) by deactivating cookies for conversion tracking, by setting your brows-er so that cookies are blocked by the domain "www.googleadservices.com", https://www.google.de/settings/ads, this setting being deleted when you delete your cookies; c) by deactivating the interest-based ads of the providers that are part of the "About Ads" self-regulation campaign via the link http://www.aboutads.info/choices, this setting being deleted when you delete your cookies; d) by permanently disabling it in your browsers Firefox, Internet Explorer, or Google Chrome, using the link http://www.google.com/settings/ads/plugin. Please note that in this case you may not be able to use all functions of this offer to their full extent.   
(4) The legal basis for processing your data is Art. 6(1)(1)(f) GDPR. Further information on Dou-bleClick by Google can be found at https://www.google.de/doubleclick and http://support.google.com/adsense/answer/2839090, as well as on data protection at Google in gen-eral: https://www.google. de/intl/en/policies/privacy. Alternatively, you can visit the website of the Network Advertising Initiative (NAI) at http://www.networkadvertising.org. Google is compliant with the EU-US Privacy Shield, <https://www.privacyshield.gov/EU-US-Framework>.

 **17.  Iridion optimization Suite**  
For user-oriented design and optimisation, our website uses the software „Iridion optimization  
Suite“ from the company Web Arts AG based in Bad Homburg, Germany.  
With the help of the software, statistical analyses of the user behaviour are carried out and based on this, content and presentation of promotional offers changed. By using this website, you consent to the processing of the data collected about you in the manner described and for the purpose stated above.  
Data collection and storage can be objected to at any time with future effect via this opt-out link: https://www.interhome.com/customer-service/privacy-policy/?iridion=notrack  
The opt-out is saved in the current browser in form of a cookie. In case of deletion of the cookie or a change of browser or device, the opt-out link must be reactivated there respectively.

 **18\. Send recommendations to friends or receive recommendations**  
Sometimes you may be able to tell a friend about a part of our website if you think it's useful to your friend. In this context, you can enter someone else's email address as the recipient of an automatical-ly generated message from our system. The message contains the link to the section of our website that you think is useful, your email address (as the sender), and your name, and is visible to recipi-ents along with the other information you entered in the subject line and main text section.   
When you receive such a message, you will see all the information entered on the "Recommend to a friend" form. This information may include the following: Email address, first name, last name, other information about you that the user of the website has entered on the form.  
Such information is only temporarily stored and processed until the email has been sent in the name of the user of the website. Information that we receive via the relevant form will only be logged for security purposes and for our protection, but will not be used for any other purpose. The information provided in this way will neither be processed by us nor will we pass it on to third parties. Our legiti-mate interest in the use of this function is to inform the recipient of our offer, as it could be of interest to the recipient - based on confirmation by a user (the legal basis for this is Article 6(1)(f) GDPR.)

 **19\. Disclosure of your personal data to other recipients  **  
(1) If you book accommodation through our website, you can choose between different payment methods.  
Your payment data will be passed on to our bank. If you decide to pay by credit card, your payment details will be transmitted to the respective payment service provider, depending on the payment method you have chosen (the legal basis for this is Art. 6(1)(1)(b) GDPR).  
The payment service provider is responsible for your payment data.  
At present Interhome AG uses the services of Mastercard Europe SA. The contact details of Master-card Europe SA, its data protection officer (if any) and other information about the processed per-sonal data are available at https://www.mastercard.de/de-de/datenschutz.html .   
Interhome AG also uses the services of Visa Europe Services Inc. The contact details of Visa Europe Services Inc., its data protection officer (if any) and further information on data protection are available at https://www.visa.de/datenschutz. 

(2) Your data will not be passed on to other third parties unless we are required to do so by law or if we are required to do so by law.

 **20\. Your rights as the affected person (data subject):**  
You have the following rights in relation to the personal data concerning you: 

  * You can ask us to confirm whether we process personal data about you and if this is the case, you have a right to obtain information about this personal data and about the infor-mation listed in Art. 15 GDPR in detail. 
  * According to Article 16 GDPR, you have the right to demand immediate correction of incor-rect personal data concerning you and, if necessary, the completion of incomplete personal data 
  * You have the right to request us to delete personal data relating to you without delay, provid-ed that one of the reasons listed in Art. 17 GDPR applies in detail 
  * You have the right to request that processing be restricted if one of the conditions set out in Art. 18 GDPR is met 
  * If the requirements of Art. 20 GDPR are fulfilled, you have the right to request data transmis-sion. 
  * According to Art. 21 GDPR, you have a right to object to the processing, which is based on Art. 6(1)(1)(f) GDPR. Processing is based on Art. 6(1)(1)(f) GDPR if, for example, pro-cessing is not necessary to fulfil a contract but is based on a balancing of interests. 
  * If we process your data on the basis of consent you have given us, you can revoke this con-sent at any time. This revocation does not affect the legality of the processing carried out on the basis of the consent until the revocation, i.e. the revocation only influences the legality of the processing of your personal data after it has been declared to us. 
  * You also have the right of appeal to a supervisory authority if you believe that the processing of personal data concerning you violates the GDPR (Art. 77 GDPR). You may exercise this right before a supervisory authority in the Member State where you are staying, working, or where the suspected violation has occurred.
